

ALESSANDRO Traiola

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am an energetic frontend addict with four years of experience creating and maintaining functional, attractive and responsive websites. I would describe myself as a self-starter with a growth mindset. I have grit, passion, and determination. There is nothing that can't be learned, there are no skills that can't be gained. I am highly adept at finding valuable projects to work on and welcome challenges wholeheartedly.

KEY COMPETENCIES

HTML, CSS JavaScript, jQuery React.js, Next.js Redux, Three.js react-three-fiber react-spring Styled Component Tailwind CSS UI/UX WordPress Elementor E-Commerce Responsive Web Design

CONTACT DETAILS

Address: Berliner Str. 74, 13189 Berlin

Number: +49 179 260 7371

Email: alessandrotraiola@gmail.com

Portfolio: aletraweb.com LinkedIn: @alessandro-traiola

WORK HISTORY

Frontend Developer

SOLID WHITE design & digital media GmbH | May 2021 - today

- Framework maintenance and features implementation
- Creation of WebGL experience with Three JS and r3f
- Design and styling of web pages

Web Designer & Developer

SAHU Media AG & Co. KG. | Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Constructed and optimized websites
- Built and optimized E-Commerce stores
- Solved design and functional problems through coding
- Created logos and other graphics
- Maintained client social media networks
- Managed customer relationships, inquiries and requests
- Awarded for outstanding website production number

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Webmasters Europe e.V.

JavaScript Developer Certification | Jun 2018 -Aug 2018

Web Design Certification | Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

alfatraining Bildungszentrum

JavaScript Developer Certification | Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 | 97/100 Mark

Learning outcomes: JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, Prototype, Angular.js, Jquery, XML, Node.js, React.js, Vue.js

Web Design Certification | Apr 2018 - Jun 2018 | Full Mark

Learning outcomes: HTML, CSS, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Academind

React.js Certification | Jan 2021 - March 2021

Learning outcomes: React.js, React Hooks, React Router, Redux, Next.js, Framer Motion

SKILLS

Visual communication Conflict resolution Eagerness to learn Working well under pressure Self-supervising

LANGUAGES

Italian (native) German (fluent) English (fluent) Spanish (beginner)



